Now let's talk about the news stocks and
Sharad Dubey has
joined us to tell us which important news and triggers are important today. Sharad, good morning,
tell me, of course, good morning, Pooja. So, over the
week, very important news has
come in, and we will bring them to you one by one. The
first important one will be Adani
Pots. Here,
last Friday's adjustment of BSE Sensex, now the
company will come in Sensex and it will replace Wi-Po. So, there will be
no movement in wallet or volumes right now, but
Adani Pots has officially come in Sensex.
Today, a block deal can happen in Car Trade
Tech, where two AIs can sell their stake at around 13,
whose value can be
₹5000000.
Reaction can be seen in stocks.
If we talk about some negative reactions, there are
three-four such news and definitely
note it. PSU banks and
MF institutions which are micro
finance institutions, especially Canara Bank
Indian.  Overseas banks have a
higher exposure to Telangana. I am saying this
because the Telangana State Government has
announced a farm
loan waiver of approximately ₹1 lakh for every farmer
in the state. So, some pressure may be
seen in the financials.
And remember, Maharashtra elections are also going to be held
at the end of the year. So, if the
focus remains on poplin schemes, then this pressure will
fall on the financial system, especially on PSUs. Let's talk about Cipla. There
is negative news flow here. Their
Goa plant received six observations
from the USFDA. Remember, this plant had
already received a warning letter.
This is important because they have
a very important launch coming up. Now, after rescinding it, let's
call it a medicine. The
launch impact of that medicine can also be seen in US sales. Let's
talk about Jeevan Small Finance Bank. They have
reduced the guidance for the financial year 2025. The
gross loan book was earlier at 25.  The
credit cost has been increased to 20, which was at 1.4 to 1.5,
now it has increased, which means it is negative
for banks, it has been increased to 1.7
and RO has also been reduced to 20,
earlier the estimate was 22, so
they have cut the guidance in four or five important parameters,
JS W Energy has got a
big project of solar hybrid power, let's
also talk about CICC Ox Green Energy, then we will consider it on June 26,
another
negative news for fund raising is coming from the pharma space,
Lupan has got Voluntary Action Initiative
's Somer Set manufacturing facility,
Somer Set is a city in the UK and
in that facility, you can say they got
Voluntary Action Initiative status, which means
some impurities have been
seen in the process or plant, Prestige
Estate is going to raise Rs 55,000 crore
through QIP and their
hospitality  There are
monetization announcements coming in the segment as well.
MCX will also be in focus. Here the company has
shortlisted candidates
who will be in focus for the post of MD and CEO.
And of course, the overhang that they had on the stock, the
software related issues that they had been facing for the
last two quarters, has also been resolved.
Tata Steel will also be in focus.
Negative news flow is coming. Here
their UK workers are going to
start their strike.
From July 8, there will be around 1500 Tata workers
who will go on an in-fit strike. If the
union says so, you will have a sentimental
negative impact. And finally, we will talk about the
government has started transmission projects worth around Rs 13,600 crore
regarding clean power. Now these are for two states,
Rajasthan and Karnataka. So there are
many beneficiaries. Of course,
Power Grid is there but the mid-cap and
small-cap stocks like KP Green
Energy, Bejal Project, Aapar Industries,
Jyoti Structures, they will also get to see benefits.  There is a
lot of important news today,
keep an eye on Adani, there will be a change in Sensex today
in which Adani is going to join, the
company is going to enter in place of Wipro, there will be a
block deal in the car trade,
negative news is coming for pharma stocks,
Lupon Cipla, keep an eye on it, there
is negative news for government banks, the focus will be on this as well
and apart from this, there is
important news for Tata Steel stock as well, the focus will be on this as well,
so these are some important news
for today, keep an eye on it, thank you Sharad
for giving this complete update.